[{"id": "5867fd58de129f03113389bc", "question": "What nationality was Roald Dahl?", "answer": "Welsh", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5989a8a3cb8751d53e7d75fc", "question": "Who won the fourth Super Bowl?", "answer": "Kansas City Chiefs", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ace", "question": "In the novel \"Don Quixote\", what swiveling structures are mistaken for giants?", "answer": "Windmills", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59f9bbe5364247bf200fb8aa", "question": "What country borders Zambia to the west?", "answer": "Angola", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe7c1de877e98cb9777897f", "question": "What was the first cave in the world to be designated a national park?", "answer": "Wind Cave", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b54c", "question": "What two colours make purple?", "answer": "Red and Blue", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e37", "question": "What children's classic first chapter is titled \"Up the Mountain to Alm-Uncle\"?", "answer": "Heidi", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59524172736d4be723796b62", "question": "Which European countries have an enclave with each other in the region of Baarle-Nassau?", "answer": "Belgium and The Netherlands (Holland)", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5be57f6c5415ba52ed6f0aaa", "question": "What type of creature is a \"sidewinder\"?", "answer": "A snake", "category": "science"}, {"id": "6013702d138175489539637f", "question": "In the 1990 film \"Home Alone\", which actor improvised all of his lines?", "answer": "John Candy -- He played his part as a favor to writer/producer John Hughes, and was paid scale (Screen Actors Guild minimum wage).", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b4dc", "question": "What two alcoholic ingredients is the traditional Martini cocktail made of?", "answer": "Gin and vermouth", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c08", "question": "What Ernest Hemingway novel is set during the Spanish Civil War?", "answer": "For Whom the Bell Tolls", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b6c3", "question": "The Chevy model known as the Camaro was originally intended to be called what?", "answer": "Panther", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c9ac", "question": "Gastritis affects which body organ?", "answer": "Stomach", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bdad", "question": "What food item shares its name with Brad and Janet's hospitable host in \"The Rocky Horror Picture Show\"?", "answer": "A frankfurter", "category": "general"}, {"id": "591c362a815febcc896f9264", "question": "Which actor took the male lead in Hitchcock's film \"The Birds\"?", "answer": "Rod Taylor", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339251", "question": "What band performed the Bond theme song \"A View to a Kill\"?", "answer": "Duran Duran", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b436", "question": "Which Italian city was severely damaged by an earthquake in 1908?", "answer": "Messina", "category": "history"}, {"id": "58c9f72db4e2c7fbd3896746", "question": "Where did Thomas Lipton open his first grocery store?", "answer": "Glasgow, Scotland", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5febac517e83c707845b20ec", "question": "What is the scientific name of the \"western lowland gorilla\"?", "answer": "Gorilla gorilla gorilla", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe7c9af877e98cb977789fa", "question": "In which city will you find the Tiergarten Park?", "answer": "Berlin", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe7bd43877e98cb97778958", "question": "What country has the most coastline?", "answer": "Canada", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f15", "question": "What author created Lilliput?", "answer": "Jonathan Swift", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b10c", "question": "In what year did both the Titanic sink and Fenway Park in Boston opened?", "answer": "1912", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a22a", "question": "The song \"I'll Be Missing You\" is a tribute to who?", "answer": "The Notorious B.I.G.", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a917", "question": "In what US state would you find Fort Ticonderoga?", "answer": "New York", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "58d1155b4fea7fe947a22265", "question": "What year did Arthur Hailey publish the novel \"The Moneychangers\"?", "answer": "1975", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b234", "question": "What athlete was born in West Baden, Indiana, in December 1956?", "answer": "Larry Bird", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59e802f7de59ea584496fe9a", "question": "Which fashion designer is popular for his \"Space Age\" look?", "answer": "Pierre Cardin", "category": "general"}, {"id": "601b491249076251badbeaab", "question": "America\u2019s first multimillionaire, John Jacob Astor, made his fortune in what?", "answer": "A fur trade monopoly -- He also made money smuggling opium to China and investing in real estate in and around New York City.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f68", "question": "In 2006, what song became the first British single to top the US charts in almost a decade?", "answer": "You're Beautiful", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5906826dff9c0647b50a809d", "question": "What physical, interactive feature did Apple introduce to their MacBook Pro laptop series in the fall of 2016?", "answer": "The \"Touch Bar\"", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a0f1", "question": "What is Ray Charles' real last name?", "answer": "Robinson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338968", "question": "What nursery rhyme character was arachnophobic?", "answer": "Little Miss Muffet", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aadb", "question": "What is the capital of Croatia?\u00a0", "answer": "Zagreb\u00a0", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fd6629fa5bfecdd737e0846", "question": "Who were Virginia and West Virginia named for?", "answer": "Queen Elizabeth I, the Virgin Queen", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a43", "question": "What Bob Marley song did Eric Clapton cover for a #1 hit?", "answer": "I Shot the Sheriff", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5963702f967692ea851899b8", "question": "What singer scored a #1 hit in 1999 with a duet with his wife, Lisa Hartman entitled, \"When I Said I Do\"?", "answer": "Clint Black", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca99", "question": "The Larynx is also called what?", "answer": "Voice box", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a49a", "question": "What was Belize called until 1973?", "answer": "British Honduras", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a5ae", "question": "What is the capitol of Morocco?", "answer": "Rabat", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bae5", "question": "What candy company makes Goobers and Raisinets?", "answer": "Nestle", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fea77aaff048f679a45abcc", "question": "What is the more common term for odontalgia?", "answer": "Toothache", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ff66c5852a821ff76ae8b11", "question": "During which year was cocaine removed as an ingredient in Coca Cola?", "answer": "1903", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc65", "question": "What do collectors call the first complete Hot Wheels line-up of cars?", "answer": "Sweet 16", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b02e", "question": "What decade saw the introduction of the Easy\u00adBake Oven, Lite Brite, and Spirograph?", "answer": "1960s", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c660", "question": "What is the purpose of \"seeding\" a cloud?", "answer": "To create rain", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe7340ceec85e375820b22c", "question": "What German fighter pilot was credited with 80 air combat victories during World War I?", "answer": "Manfred von Richthofen", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113393b6", "question": "Who does Jabba intend to feed to Sarlacc in the movie \"Star Wars - Return of the Jedi\"?", "answer": "Luke and Han", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339899", "question": "Which Indiana Jones movie was first released in 1981?", "answer": "Raiders of the Lost Ark", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aaa0", "question": "What is the capital of Niger?", "answer": "Niamey", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59ae954b574a5ce6b56b8252", "question": "Which river made the Grand Canyon?", "answer": "Colorado River", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339161", "question": "Who was the commander of the Starship Enterprise?", "answer": "Captain James T. Kirk", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fdab5750b8cce1e6fda704d", "question": "According to the jingle, which coffee brand is the best part of waking up?", "answer": "Folgers", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e25", "question": "What 1904 play was subtitled \"The Boy Who Wouldn't Grow Up\"?", "answer": "Peter Pan", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113392c5", "question": "Eric Carmen's hit song \"Hungry Eyes\" has been used in a popular TV ad campaign for what snack food?", "answer": "M&Ms", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133967c", "question": "In the TV show \"The Simpsons\", what movie star asked Homer to fix his movie?", "answer": "Mel Gibson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113392f2", "question": "In the movie \"Saving Private Ryan\", how many of the Ryan brothers were soldiers?", "answer": "Four", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ffb59b55dad637d903c8814", "question": "What is the modern name for Van Diemen\u2019s Land?", "answer": "Tasmania", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c1e7", "question": "Who is more commonly known as the Michelin Man?", "answer": "Bibendum", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5e94d1fc5ea27d7a1303aed6", "question": "In what US state is the Naismith Memorial Basketball Hall of Fame located?", "answer": "Massachusetts", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc73", "question": "What car company takes its name from the Japanese word for the constellation Pleiades?", "answer": "Subaru", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c57c", "question": "What volcanic rock floats in water?", "answer": "Pumice", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c84d", "question": "In what organ of the human body would you find the cochlea?", "answer": "The ear", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ae69", "question": "What did Ronald Reagan disclose he was suffering from in 1994?", "answer": "Alzheimer's Disease", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c755", "question": "What is the opposite of insulin and secreted by the pancreas?", "answer": "Glucagon", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a010", "question": "What TV show's famed \"puffy shirt\" is in the Smithsonian today?", "answer": "Seinfeld's", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb35", "question": "What sign of the zodiac are you if you were born on Leap Day?", "answer": "Pisces", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59071bf03745b36be73039c6", "question": "What meat is illegal in the Chew comics universe?", "answer": "Chicken", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a433", "question": "What is the capital of Spain?", "answer": "Madrid", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a94d", "question": "What two \"Great\" lakes are the largest two lakes entirely within Canada?", "answer": "Great Bear and Great Slave lakes", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c7c6", "question": "Who won a Nobel Prize for discovering inert gases?", "answer": "William Ramsey", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b876", "question": "How many total candles do you need to light a menorah properly for the entire eight nights of Hanukkah?", "answer": "44", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c0a0", "question": "How many gallons does a tun barrel typically hold?", "answer": "252", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c032", "question": "Pyrophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Fire", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fde51c8c6c6b019850c9a91", "question": "Which Aegean Island's volcanic eruption may have possibly produced the Atlantis legend?", "answer": "Thera", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59ae9363574a5ce6b56b823a", "question": "What was Queen Victoria's first name?", "answer": "Alexandrina", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338caf", "question": "What artist pioneered Abstract Impressionism in 1948?", "answer": "Jackson Pollack", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339bf3", "question": "What year was Frank Sinatra born in?", "answer": "1915", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5c3e97e4ebfabb9c85d8a967", "question": "What is the stage name of Harry Webb?", "answer": "Cliff Richard", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa55", "question": "What is the capital of South Korea?", "answer": "Seoul", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b7ff", "question": "What do opposite faces of a die always add up to?", "answer": "Seven", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b6a1", "question": "What US road sign is typically shaped like a triangle?", "answer": "Yield", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fd96e5b23c87fd04dd15e36", "question": "Which U.S. president owned a pet hyena?", "answer": "Theodore Roosevelt", "category": "history"}, {"id": "6008dd47f4f3bc4a292f861f", "question": "When was the last time when the U.S officially declared war?", "answer": "June 5, 1942", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e9c", "question": "What Steinbeck novel takes its title from a poem by Julia Ward Howe?", "answer": "The Grapes of Wrath", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5b7abc6f6490a8cc1a6e529a", "question": "What does the \"c\" in \"E=mc\u00b2\" represent?", "answer": "The speed of light", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fd96c8623c87fd04dd15e26", "question": "Which U.S. president received offers to play in the NFL?", "answer": "Gerald Ford", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe7389beec85e375820b265", "question": "What currency is used in South Africa?", "answer": "Rand", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "601b4c5049076251badbead1", "question": "The term \"first family\" came into popularity under which U.S. President?", "answer": "John F. Kennedy -- Comedian/Kennedy impressionist Vaughn Meader titled his Grammy-winning 1962 album \"First Family\".", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59e80464de59ea584496fea4", "question": "What are the names of the two adult Dalmatians in the novel \"The Hundred and One Dalmatians\"?", "answer": "Pongo and Missis", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe76c52eec85e375820b2d0", "question": "Hollywood legend Clint Eastwood was once mayor of which city?", "answer": "Carmel, California", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339876", "question": "Trigun, a popular western sci-fi anime, consisted of how many episodes?", "answer": "26", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "600a2704e958e8c9f3127313", "question": "Where did the Mayflower land in New England in 1620?", "answer": "Cape Cod - The Mayflower sailed from England to the \u201cNew World,\u201d landing in Plymouth Harbor along the shores of Cape Cod.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe4ec2f06d333868d34d761", "question": "In which year was the White Australia Policy formally abolished?", "answer": "1972", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d45", "question": "What actress shaved her head for her role in the movie \"Anna and the King\"?", "answer": "Bai Ling", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b210", "question": "Who was assassinated by Charlotte Corday?", "answer": "Jean-Paul Marat", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ff3c2f64f032c0db195b488", "question": "What charter did a group of English barons force King John to sign in 1215 at Runnymede?", "answer": "Magna Carta", "category": "history"}, {"id": "60173bec44491cbd7c5a17a1", "question": "Which Roman Emperor made the seven-day week official part of the existing Julian calendar?", "answer": "Constantine the Great", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad5e", "question": "For what does the \"F.\" stand in the name F. Lee Bailey?", "answer": "Francis", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b4a8", "question": "Which country were the 1948 Winter Olympic Games?", "answer": "Switzerland", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a058", "question": "Adrenalize, Retro Active, and Pyromania are albums from which British hard rock band?", "answer": "Def Leppard", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "600242bc4be4723ccac2218b", "question": "Which French novelist wrote the seven-volume novel \"In Search of Lost Time\" (often translated as \"Remembrance of Times Past\")?", "answer": "Marcel Proust", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d7f", "question": "Who was the real-life model for the character of Abe Ravelstein in the novel \"Ravelstein\"?", "answer": "Allan Bloom", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339528", "question": "Who directed the 1990 movie \"La Femme Nikita\"?", "answer": "Luc Besson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf80", "question": "What is a tightrope walker called?", "answer": "Funambulist", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59a1a1e512f2a7826b9b8716", "question": "What was the name given to the French goverment which collaborated with the Nazis?", "answer": "Vichy", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339153", "question": "What do ghouls typically feast on?", "answer": "Human flesh", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b1cc", "question": "Whose execution caused the famed Spanish Armada to sail against England?", "answer": "Mary, Queen of Scots'", "category": "history"}, {"id": "596dfd319616e6c6d4eba4f4", "question": "What is a baby swan called?", "answer": "A Cygnet", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad8f", "question": "Which Protestant Reformer outlawed the Feast of Saint Nicholas in 1545?", "answer": "Martin Luther", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fec861eec223966ae8f880e", "question": "Renaud Lavillenie and Sergey Bubka are members of what event's exclusive 6-meter-high club?", "answer": "Pole vault", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5cb70cdcf96e155acab35d30", "question": "What country once technically fought a war against a species of bird?", "answer": "Australia, \"The Emu War\"", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c5ac", "question": "The troposphere, stratosphere and mesosphere all make part of the Earth's what?", "answer": "Atmosphere", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a8d", "question": "What sitcom drew an audience of 80.4 million viewers for its final episode, in 1993?", "answer": "Cheers", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58b36f471c3f17ccc40c8e0d", "question": "How many Academy Awards was the film \"The Sixth Sense\" nominated for?", "answer": "Six", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388e8", "question": "What does M.C. stand for in M.C. Escher's name?", "answer": "Maurits Cornelis", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab94", "question": "In what present-day country is Mount Ararat located?", "answer": "Turkey", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc5a", "question": "What year was \"Cirque du Soleil\" founded?", "answer": "1984", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f1f", "question": "What author created Discworld?", "answer": "Terry Pratchett", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fec83ccec223966ae8f87f9", "question": "The late Michael Jackson is widely known as the \"King of Pop\". But who is considered the \"Queen of Pop\"?", "answer": "Madonna", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b819", "question": "What sport has official rules to cover \"tea intervals\"?", "answer": "Cricket", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad6d", "question": "What explorer was the first to sail around the southern tip of South America, and name it Cape Horn?", "answer": "William Schouten", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c482", "question": "Are polar bears carnivores or omnivores?", "answer": "Carnivores", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab5a", "question": "What sea does the river Elbe flow into?", "answer": "North Sea", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c819", "question": "In what part of the body would you find amniotic fluid?", "answer": "The uterus", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac3f", "question": "What Roman god is January named for?", "answer": "Janus", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a6e4", "question": "What is the capital of the US state of Georgia?", "answer": "Atlanta", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5990f8abfa5fdd6dd25324f0", "question": "Which city is home to Colman's mustard?", "answer": "Norwich", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d1f", "question": "Helen Keller was related to what former Confederate general?", "answer": "Robert E. Lee", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c435", "question": "What is the only bone in the human body that doesn't connect with any other?", "answer": "Hyoid", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe7694ceec85e375820b2b0", "question": "What word is best described by \"irregular beat of the heart or other muscle\"?", "answer": "Fibrillation", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ee6", "question": "What is another name for a quaver?", "answer": "An eighth note", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339279", "question": "In season 14 of the TV show \"Big Brother\" what 5 players make up the quack pack?", "answer": "Dan, Danielle, Britney, Shane and Ian", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "60078566bd51d85e222ab65e", "question": "Who said: \"I\u2019m the president of the United States, and I\u2019m not going to eat any more broccoli\"?", "answer": "George H.W. Bush (He once made a joke that the workers in the Office of Personnel Management would get merit pay \"in broccoli\").", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb4a", "question": "What is the name for Germany's high-speed highways?", "answer": "Autobahn", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf0f", "question": "Where does the famous \"running of the bulls\" take place?", "answer": "Pamplona", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113389d0", "question": "What nursery rhyme character was rich on Monday but broke on Sunday?", "answer": "Solomon Grundy", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339966", "question": "In the TV show \"The Simpsons\", what is the name of the comic book store?", "answer": "The Android's Dungeon and Baseball Card Shop", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fdc0ce7469bb8041d07a056", "question": "How do you say \"Merry Christmas\" in France?", "answer": "Joyeux Noel", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391a9", "question": "Who voices the character of scientist and inventor Professor John I.Q. Nerdelbaum Frink Jr. on \"The Simpsons\"?", "answer": "Hank Azaria", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388bb", "question": "In Shakespeare's \"Romeo and Juliet\", what is Juliet's surname?", "answer": "Capulet", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113392eb", "question": "In the 1991 movie \"Thelma and Louise\" who plays the part of Thelma?", "answer": "Geena Davis", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59524521736d4be723796b6b", "question": "What French impressionist painter died in 1926", "answer": "Claude Monet", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59049ca0cf93664eb10486a8", "question": "Which famous rapper died on Friday, September 13, 1996?", "answer": "Tupac Shakur", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391f0", "question": "HBO's TV show \"True Blood\" is based on a book series by whom?", "answer": "Charlene Harris", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ffb68455dad637d903c8841", "question": "Which country, other than Switzerland, uses the Swiss franc?", "answer": "Liechtenstein", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ef6", "question": "What horror movie was based on the novel \"Ratman's Notebooks\"?", "answer": "Willard", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58ab1a7bbaab681b09292194", "question": "What celebrity\u2019s car was fixed and raced in the 2009 documentary \u201cLove the Beast\u201d", "answer": "Eric Bana's", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b639", "question": "What brand of seasoning was named after a famous prime rib restaurant?", "answer": "Lawry's", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf05", "question": "What large red flower is the floral emblem of New South Wales?", "answer": "Waratah", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a6c4", "question": "Lake Tahoe is located in which US states?", "answer": "California and Nevada", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a1be", "question": "Lesley Hornby became more famous as who?", "answer": "Twiggy", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6018bc34d96d05b23b281654", "question": "In which country did Buddhism originate?", "answer": "Nepal", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ac6", "question": "Playwright Thomas Lanier \"Tennessee\" Williams was born in what US state?", "answer": "Mississippi", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fecd67fec223966ae8f88d4", "question": "Who says, \"Frankly my dear, I don\u2019t give a damn\" in \"Gone with the Wind\"?", "answer": "Rhett Butler", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5b23aed38f1a2238a7cb2b3d", "question": "What two countries noticed that they had the same flag at the 1936 Olympics in Berlin?", "answer": "Haiti and Liechtenstein", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e27", "question": "What began as a ligature of the letters \"e\" and \"t\"?", "answer": "The ampersand", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339819", "question": "The I-V-vi-IV chord progression is commonly referred to by what alliterative name?", "answer": "Pop-punk progression", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338bb4", "question": "Which famous number was dreaded by people in Orwell\u2019s 1984?", "answer": "101", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b51", "question": "In Greek mythology, Jocasta is the mother of who?", "answer": "Oedipus", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339784", "question": "What saxophonist released the 1964 album \"A Love Supreme\"?", "answer": "John Coltrane", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339485", "question": "Who stars as Walter Fielding Jr. in the 1986 movie \"The Money Pit\"?", "answer": "Tom Hanks", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fde52fac6c6b019850c9a99", "question": "Who was arrested after killing 35 people on the Australian island of Tasmania in 1996?", "answer": "Martin Bryant", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5febab537e83c707845b20e7", "question": "Which planet is referred to as the \"jewel of the solar system\"?", "answer": "Saturn", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a963", "question": "What split up into Gondwanaland and Laurasia?", "answer": "Pangaea", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "6014c5f3fbde8045e48466b3", "question": "A \"bloat\" refers to a group of what animal?", "answer": "Hippopotamus -- A group of hippos consist of 10 to 20 females, their young, and one male hippo.", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e1f", "question": "What artist sold only one painting, \"The Red Vineyard\", during his lifetime?", "answer": "Vincent van Gogh", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "58d077e0870e6f05ba600868", "question": "Who directed the 1995 film \"Boys on the Side\"?", "answer": "Herbert Ross", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c925", "question": "What is a characteristic of a \"nimbus\" cloud?", "answer": "Rain", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ecd", "question": "Who hosted the TV show \"This Old House\" for the first ten seasons?", "answer": "Bob Vila", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c65d", "question": "How many feet does a snail have?", "answer": "One", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b82", "question": "How many symphonies did Ludvig van Beethoven compose?", "answer": "9", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c2bc", "question": "What are the three main types of sugar?", "answer": "Glucose, fructose and sucrose", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c7f9", "question": "What is the surgical knife called an \"izmel\" used for?", "answer": "Circumcision at a bris", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c9d2", "question": "What word is used for a male deer?", "answer": "Buck", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59f47342cfb6472aeed499d5", "question": "What is a \"Papoose\"?", "answer": "A Native American Child", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa8d", "question": "Dakar is the capital of which African country?", "answer": "Senegal", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133949a", "question": "Who played European John Blackthorne in the miniseries \"Shogun\"?", "answer": "Richard Chamberlain", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133aee2", "question": "Which war did the Treaty of Portsmouth end in 1905?", "answer": "The Russo-Japanese War", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab13", "question": "Hobart is the capital of which Australian state?", "answer": "Tasmania", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c0cf", "question": "The berries of the juniper tree are used to flavour which alcoholic drink?\u00a0", "answer": "Gin\u00a0", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a98", "question": "What early rock and roll pioneer's real first and middle name was Charles Hardin?", "answer": "Buddy Holly", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133908f", "question": "Who is the Roman equivalent of the Greek goddess Eirene?", "answer": "Pax", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133adb7", "question": "Portia Simpson-Miller was the leader of what country?", "answer": "Jamaica", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ad7e910b24f84e0b9f9ffc8", "question": "What year did Botswana gain its independence from the United Kingdom?", "answer": "1966", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b35d", "question": "Who was the first American scientist to win a Nobel prize?", "answer": "Albert Michelson", "category": "history"}, {"id": "6014c781fbde8045e48466c3", "question": "What was the first masculine name given to a hurricane?", "answer": "Bob", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe65bfb1f3c0ead6880d60b", "question": "According to the Bible, where was Apollos from?", "answer": "Alexandria", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af83", "question": "Which US president asked the US congress to declare war on Japan in 1941?", "answer": "Franklin D. Roosevelt", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113392fe", "question": "After returning from death in the movie \"The Lord of the Rings\", Gandalf the Grey's name changes to what?", "answer": "Gandalf the White", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b077", "question": "What was the last name of Civil Rights activist Malcolm X?", "answer": "Little", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b5d4", "question": "How many ounces of coffee are there in a Starbucks \"tall\" size?", "answer": "12", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe656e6ae7e414034b5aed3", "question": "What was the name of the German offensive operation in October 1941 to take Moscow before winter?", "answer": "Operation Harpoon", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fec866aec223966ae8f8810", "question": "What did writer Stephen King do with his royalty check he received for the film \"The Shawshank Redemption?", "answer": "King had the uncashed check framed and mailed it to the film's director, Frank Darabont.", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ae32", "question": "What American Civil War general was nicknamed \"Young Napoleon\"?", "answer": "General George McClellan", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5a4d9a6708b8581f80b092bc", "question": "What did the United Nations General Assembly designate 2017 as?", "answer": "International Year of Sustainable Tourism for Development", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5febaa3e7e83c707845b20dd", "question": "How many main layers make up the earth's atmosphere?", "answer": "5", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fdabcbc0b8cce1e6fda705f", "question": "Which food can be called \"marrowfat\"?", "answer": "Processed peas", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5bfe0092b668d7dfe168b5c3", "question": "What sports figure is nicknamed \"Beefy\"?", "answer": "Ian Botham", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be00", "question": "What feline was the first-ever character balloon in the Macy's Thanksgiving Day Parade?", "answer": "Felix the Cat", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58ab953a86faa38a764be513", "question": "What year did BMW debut the M5?", "answer": "1985", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339bca", "question": "What year was Boy George born in?", "answer": "1961", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a350", "question": "What Russian city boasts the Hermitage Museum?", "answer": "St. Petersburg", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ae60", "question": "What do the 36 columns surrounding the Lincoln Memorial represent?", "answer": "The number of states at the time of Lincoln's death", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a97a", "question": "What nation's legislative body is named The Great Khural?", "answer": "Mongolia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe73497eec85e375820b238", "question": "The Hanging Gardens of Babylon were built by which king?", "answer": "Nebuchadnezzar II", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fd661cea5bfecdd737e083f", "question": "How many rooms are in Buckingham Palace?", "answer": "775", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f19", "question": "What author created Utopia?", "answer": "Thomas More", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339223", "question": "What is the name of Futurama's first episode aired in 1999?", "answer": "Space Pilot 3000", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe4edc106d333868d34d770", "question": "What do you call the moveable indicator on a Ouija board which is shaped like a heart?", "answer": "Planchette", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113392ff", "question": "In the movie \"Ghost\", what was Sam Wheat's profession?", "answer": "A banker", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c87", "question": "Who has the only speaking part in Mel Brooks' \"Silent Movie\"?", "answer": "Marcel Marceau", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5e8a66949a45431f553a9ccf", "question": "Who is the original presenter and Taskmaster on the UK television show \"Taskmaster\"?", "answer": "Greg Davies", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b150", "question": "In what year did the Berlin Wall come down?", "answer": "1989", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5900873f5304ceedb84e8995", "question": "What drink began in Morison's drug store in Waco, Texas in 1885?", "answer": "Dr. Pepper", "category": "history"}, {"id": "58ab149fbaab681b09292176", "question": "What year did GM first introduce the Corvette?", "answer": "1953", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d4d", "question": "What actress shaved her head for her role in the movie \"Caged\"?", "answer": "Eleanor Parker", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc01", "question": "In what year did photography become an integral part of Vogue Magazine?", "answer": "1913", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a232", "question": "What instrument is jazz musician Charlie Mingus mostly associated with?", "answer": "Double Bass", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b4c2", "question": "What year was Indira Gandhi born?", "answer": "1917", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe8f74701dd7bf43be5e836", "question": "The board game Parcheesi is based off a board game from what country?", "answer": "India", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a8e7", "question": "What city is home to the University of Haiti?", "answer": "Port-au-Prince", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe8fefa01dd7bf43be5e85f", "question": "Ablutophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Cleaning, bathing or washing", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58b8cf0c94b094db915830ac", "question": "In which country would you find the Aya Castle?", "answer": "Japan", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b926", "question": "What color does the bride traditionally wear in China?", "answer": "Red", "category": "general"}, {"id": "60062a6ec9d816e292245c18", "question": "What Jewish German-born American sculptor helped usher in the postminimal art movement in the 1960s?", "answer": "Eva Hesse (She is known for her pioneering work in materials such as latex, fiberglass, and plastics.)", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b0a5", "question": "What is the first name of Fidel Castro's brother, who became Cuba's acting president when Fidel fell ill?", "answer": "Raul", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bcf5", "question": "What's the name of the Jolly Green Giant's sidekick?", "answer": "Little Green Sprout", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133904e", "question": "Which author wrote the \"Redwall\" series of novels?", "answer": "Brian Jacques", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b015", "question": "What noted black leader organized the first \u201cMillion Man March\u201d in 1995?", "answer": "Rev. Louis Farrakhan", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c1df", "question": "In the restaurant world, what does \"Blue-plate special\" refer to?", "answer": "Low-priced specials that change daily", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b2f1", "question": "What US state has been governed by Philip La Follette and Tommy Thompson?", "answer": "Wisconsin", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5e5f0fc7d274615ecf514536", "question": "Which plant has the most genes of any living plant or animal?", "answer": "Paris Japonica", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a1b1", "question": "Which heroine comes from Amphipolis?", "answer": "Xena", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "592eb0f6f83302ff91e464a2", "question": "What company makes the Vince Lombardi Trophy?", "answer": "Tiffany & Co.", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c5b", "question": "In what novel would you find the character known as the Artful Dodger?", "answer": "Oliver Twist", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c969", "question": "What is the orbital period of Uranus?", "answer": "84 years", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe7c99e877e98cb977789f8", "question": "On the first of November, Spain celebrates \"Todos los Santos\" which translates to what in English?", "answer": "All Saints Day", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ff66e6952a821ff76ae8b1b", "question": "What did people often say for photos before \"cheese\"?", "answer": "When Richard Beard, Britain's first portrait photographer, began taking family portraits, he told his clients to say \"prunes\".", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133948f", "question": "How long did the 1929 Academy Award ceremony last?", "answer": "15 minutes", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b169", "question": "What was the name of the site used to build the Empire State Building?", "answer": "John Thompson Farm", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c31f", "question": "What is the most common element in air?", "answer": "Nitrogen", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a903", "question": "What major river runs through the city of London?", "answer": "Thames", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59ae92d2574a5ce6b56b8232", "question": "Who had a hit with the song \"Mah Na Mah Na\"?", "answer": "Piero Umiliani", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339bae", "question": "What was the last name of the main family on the TV show \"3rd Rock From the Sun\"?", "answer": "Solomon", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c963", "question": "Parr, Smolt and Grilse are lifecycle stages for what fish?", "answer": "Salmon", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113389d5", "question": "How old is Annie, according to the musical's script?", "answer": "11", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a91e", "question": "In what US state would you find Fort Donelson?", "answer": "Tennessee", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338fc3", "question": "What's the opposite of \"synonym\"?", "answer": "Antonym", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ca2", "question": "First published in 1988, who wrote the book \"A Brief History of Time\"?", "answer": "Stephen Hawking", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a2cc", "question": "Which 1947 film, starring Cary Grant and Loretta Young was directed by Henry Koster?", "answer": "The Bishop's Wife", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5e38d000f6c8a670a7957c55", "question": "What is the name of the first single by the Korean girl-group \"Red Velvet\"?", "answer": "Happiness", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c21e", "question": "Who was Randy Mario Poffo better known as?", "answer": "\"Macho Man\" Randy Savage", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b5f9", "question": "Coffee heiress Abigail Folger was one of the victims of which criminal?", "answer": "Charles Manson", "category": "general"}, {"id": "601b4b6649076251badbeac4", "question": "Maya Angelou spoke at the inauguration of which U.S. President?", "answer": "Maya Angelou recited her poem \"On the Pulse of Morning,\" at President Bill Clinton's first inauguration in 1993.", "category": "history"}]